JONNA PANDER | DATA SCIENCE

Austin, TX · 512-964-2000

$jpander@gmail.com \cdot linkedin.com/in/jonnapander \cdot jonnapander.github.io \cdot github.com/jonnapander$

Environmental Consultant turned Information Solutions Consultant turned Data Science Professional with 3 years experience working with data and over a decade in the consulting industry helping clients solve problems.

SKILLS

- Python, R
- SQL
- Seaborn, Numpy, Scikit-Learn
- Data Analysis & Visualization
- Machine Learning

- Deep Learning
- Regressions
- Databases (SSMS, FileMaker)
- Gi
- Tableau

PROJECTS

Reddit Classification with NLP - API | NLP | Machine Learning

Scraped data from Reddit threads and built a binary classifier to identify which subreddit a given post originated from.

Extracting Flood Depths From Images - Python | Deep Learning

Utilized VGG16 architecture and keras to estimate depth of flood water from images of hurricane floods.

House Price Prediction - Python | Machine Learning

Used linear regression to estimate housing saleprice based on dataset with over 80 features.

EXPERIENCE

APRIL 2020 – JULY 2020, AUSTIN, TX DATA SCIENCE FELLOW, GENERAL ASSEMBLY

 Python, Data Cleaning/Exploration (Pandas, NumPy, SciPy), Machine Learning and Regression/Classification-based Modeling (Scikit-Learn, Statsmodels, Keras and TensorFlow), Webscraping/Data Mining (Requests, BeautifulSoup) and Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

JULY 2015 – FEBRUARY 2020, AUSTIN, TX

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT, BSI EHS SERVICES AND SOLUTIONS

- Automated processing of chemical inventory data using SQL, SQL Server Management Studio, and FileMakerPro
- Led cross-functional teams in custom software configurations of enterprise Software as a Service (SaaS) to meet clients' specific needs
- Created ad-hoc analysis reports with SQL Server Report Builder and business intelligence (BI) dashboards
- Interfaced with regulatory agencies to assist clients in compliance and permitting
- Prepared technical documentation in the form of user manuals and process descriptions

FEBRUARY 2011 - NOVEMBER 2014, AUSTIN, TX

ENVIRONMENTAL CONSULTANT, SPIRIT ENVIRONMENTAL, LLC

 Determined calculation methodologies and prepared emissions calculations in Excel, process flow diagram drawings, site maps, regulatory reviews, process descriptions (technical writing), and application forms for permitting sources of air emissions

EDUCATION

JULY 2020, AUSTIN, TX

DATA SCIENCE IMMERSIVE, GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Three-month program focused on real-world applications of data science principles and best practices including, data acquisition, data cleaning and wrangling, predictive modeling, and visualization strategies.

DECEMBER 2006, COLLEGE STATION, TX

BS RANGELAND ECOLOGY & MANAGEMENT, TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY

This degree program is now called Ecosystem Science & Management. Coursework was heavy in plant identification and environmental assessments.